A Guide to the Fairfax County History Commission Records, 1967-2019
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Fairfax County History Commission Records, 1967-2019
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 09-01
12 linear feet
The Fairfax County History Commission Records consists of 12 linear feet and spans the years 1967-2019, and contains correspondence; financial records; certificates; resolutions; notes; newspaper articles; photocopies; research; photographs; rosters; brochures; programs; coins; and other ephemera. The collection documents the activities and history of the Fairfax County History Commission, as well as the commission’s predecessor, the Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission.
Fairfax County History Commission
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
This collection has largely been artificially assembled by Virginia Room staff since the 1970s. Files from the Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission and the Fairfax County History Commission were originally retained by the Fairfax County Office of Comprehensive Planning. After the establishment of the county’s Archives and Records Management Branch, records were later transferred there in 1992. As early as 1976, History Commissioners simultaneously donated miscellaneous records and documents to the Virginia Room. In February 2008, History Commission records retained at the County Archives were destroyed as per the Library of Virginia’s record retention policy, but records deemed historic were transferred to the Virginia Room. Financial records were added to this collection by Commissioner Elise Murray in August 2015. Files on the Fairfax County History Conference were added by Commissioner Lynne Garvey-Hodge in March 2018. Commissioner Jack Hiller created and maintained files on the commission’s historical makers which were added to this collection in January 2019 by Commissioner Debbie Robison. The collection was organized and processed in 2019 for the Fairfax County History Commission’s 50th anniversary.
Historical and Biographical Information
On April 9, 1969, the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors appointed the Fairfax County History Commission to advise the county government and promote public interest in matters involving the history of Fairfax County. The History Commission grew out of the Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission established by the Board of Supervisors in 1965. The 20-member body maintains and monitors the Fairfax County Inventory of Historic Sites, Historic Overlay Districts, the Historical Marker program, hosts an annual history conference, participates in the Section 106 review process, and works closely with the county’s Department of Planning and Zoning, Architectural Review Board, Park Authority, Cultural Resource Management and Protection programs, and the Virginia Room. The History Commission was largely influential in creating a program to index and microfilm the Fairfax County Circuit Court Records and prompted the creation of the county’s archaeology and records management programs.
Scope and Content
Series 1: Subject Files, 1967-2019, Boxes 1-3
This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. Materials include correspondence, newspaper articles, reports, notes, certificates and resolutions, index cards, charters, photocopies, and rubber stamps. Early records from the History Commission’s first two years are also included.
Series 2: Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1967-1971, Boxes 3-4
These files contain records relating to the History Commission’s predecessor, the Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission founded in 1965. Included are correspondence, by-laws, resumes, and other records. The Commission also maintained files for local agencies and files for a Commission-sponsored Chain-of-Title research study. The files are arranged alphabetically.
Series 3: Rosters, 1974-2017, Box 4
These files contain rosters and resumes for Fairfax County History Commission members. Also included is a compiled 1969-2017 roster of Fairfax County History Commissioners created by Commissioner Carole Herrick. The files are arranged chronologically.
Series 4: Events, 1980-2019, Boxes 5-6
These files include records for events hosted by the Fairfax County History Commission including the annual history conference and anniversary celebrations. Files include programs, news articles, photographs, video footage on DVD, photographs, correspondence, notes, and event handouts. Files are arranged chronologically by event date.
Series 5: George Washington 250th Celebration Commission, 1976-1982, Box 7
In 1978, the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors appointed a George Washington 250th Birthday Celebration Commission to plan activities and to stimulate interest for a year-long celebration to be held in the county in 1982. These files were maintained by the History Commission of which several of its members served on the 250th Commission. Included are calendars, correspondence, memorandum, resolutions, newspaper clippings, programs, speech materials, invitations, and commemorative bronze medallion coins. Files are arranged alphabetically.
Series 6: Publications, 1970-2018, Box 8
The History Commission has printed and sponsored several publications throughout its history. Files in this series include brochures, maps, correspondence, notes, and other materials related to publications. Files are arranged alphabetically.
Series 7: Awards, 1982-1998, Boxes 8-9
These files include records for the History Commission’s awards program. Included are photographs from the Distinguished Service Award ceremonies.
Series 8: Financial Records, 1975-2005, Boxes 9-12
Commissioner Elise Murray maintained most of these financial records as the long-time treasurer of the History Commission. Included are receipts, bank statements, notes, correspondence, cancelled checks, check register, budget materials, and financial records for History Commission publications. Files are arranged alphabetically.
Series 9: Historical Markers, 1991-2019
Sub-series 9-1: Historical Marker Files, 1991-2018, Boxes 13-22
Commissioner Jack Hiller initially created and maintained these files on historical markers, and they were later maintained by Commissioner Debbie Robison. The files are arranged alphabetically and contain photographs, correspondence, dedication programs, news articles, marker text, notes, and research used for the creation of the markers.
Sub-series 9-2: Subject Files, 1992-2015, Boxes 23-24
These subject files contain correspondence, minutes, notes, and other papers relating to historical markers. Also included is a badge Jack Hiller wore as a History Commissioner. Files are arranged alphabetically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
Minutes of the Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Committee and Fairfax County History Commission are cataloged in the Virginia Room under VRARE 975.529 F
Index Terms
County officials and employees - Virginia - Fairfax County; Fairfax County (Va.) - History; Fairfax County (Va.) - Officials and employees; Fairfax County History Commission; Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission; Historical markers - Virginia - Fairfax County
Container List
- Series 1: Subject Files, 1967-2019
  - Certificates and Resolutions, 1999-2019 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Charter, 1969-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Appointment and Resignation of History Commission Members, 1985-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Honorary Advisory Members, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Court Order Books (photocopies), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fairfax Coat-of-Arms, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fairfax County History Commission 1969 Records, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fairfax County History Commission 1970 Records, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax County History Museum, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax County Inventory of Historic Sites, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax County Inventory of Historic Sites, 1973 February (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fairfax County Inventory of Historic Sites, 1976 October (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax County Inventory of Historic Sites, 2002 July (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fairfax County License Plate, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fairfax County Officials Chronological Listing, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fairfax Heritage Society, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - History Commission Retreat, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Index Cards, Fairfax County Directories 1854, 1855, 1877, 1884, 1888, 1890, 1897, 1906, 1907, 1911, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lorton Prison/Laurel Hill National Register of Historic Places Nomination, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mission, 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mortensen, 1970-71 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper articles, 1979-2015 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Procedures and Bylaws, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Public Forums, 1984 July (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Rubber stamps "Fairfax County History Commission", Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series 2: Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1967-1971
  - Agencies - Fairfax County Cultural Association, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Agencies - Northern Virginia Regional Park Authority, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Agencies - Virginia History Federation, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Agencies - Virginia Travel Council, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bayard Evans Resignation, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - By-Laws, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chain-of-Title Research Study, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Consolidation Plan for Park and Recreation Programs in Fairfax County, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Chain-of-Title Research, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Northern Virginia Regional Park Authority, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Historic Preservation Bulletin, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Historic Preservation/Conservation Easements, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Pioneer America Society Fairfax County Chapter, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Resumes (William D. Flandermeyer, John L. Frisbee, Stuart C. Schwartz, Edith M. Sprouse), 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Series 3: Rosters, 1974-2017
  - History Commission Member List, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - History Commission Member List, 1983-1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - History Commission Member List, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - History Commission Member List, 1998-2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - History Commission Member Resumes, 1988-2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "List of Past Fairfax County History Commissioners 1969-2017", 2017 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series 4: Events, 1980-2019
  - Northern Virginia Regional History Conference, 1980 March 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax Historical Landmarks Preservation Commission 20th Anniversary [contains photos], 1985 October 25 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax County History Commission 30th Anniversary [contains photos], 1998 November 8 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 10th Annual Virginia Festival for the Book, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1st Annual Fairfax County History Conference [contains photos and DVD], 2005 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 2nd Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 3rd Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 4th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 5th Annual Fairfax County History Conference [contains DVD], 2009 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 6th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 7th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 8th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 9th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 10th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 11th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 12th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2016 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 13th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 14th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2018 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - World War I Armistice Centennial Ceremony, 2018 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 15th Annual Fairfax County History Conference, 2019 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Series 5: George Washington 250th Celebration Commission, 1976-1982
  - Bronze medallion coins [2 coins], 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bronze medallion coins [2 coins], 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Calendars of Events, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Commission Origin and History, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - County Resolutions, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - GW Parkway Material, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Memorandum, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Programs, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Speech Material, 1976-1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Stationary Invitations, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Series 6: Publications, 1970-2018
  - Beth Mitchell 1760 Map, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Beth Mitchell 1860 Property Identification Map of Fairfax County, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Brochure, "Fairfax County Then and Now", 1972-1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Brochure, "The Fairfax County History Commission", 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Brochure, "The Fairfax County History Commission", 1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Brochure, "The Fairfax County History Commission", 2004-2005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Brochure, "The Fairfax County History Commission", 2018 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Brochure, "Visit Fairfax County 1970", 1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Contracts, 1985-2007 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Joseph Harsh, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Historical Publications, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Map, "African American landowners, churches, schools, and businesses: Fairfax County, Virginia (1860-1900)", 1989, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Union Mills Study Commissioned, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - "The Preservation of History in Fairfax County, Virginia", Netherton Project, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Series 7: Awards, 1982-1998
  - Awards Program, 1995-1998 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1982-1988 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Mary McNeill Fahringer Award - Volunteer Applications and Procedures, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Photo, Distinguished Service Award Ceremony, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Photo, Distinguished Service Award Ceremony, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Photos, Distinguished Service Award Ceremony: Audrey Moore, John Terry Chase, Malcolm Richardson, Black Women United, and Patrick Reed, 1990 May (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Photos, Distinguished Service Award Ceremony, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Photos, Distinguished Service Award Ceremony: Rev. Clinton W. Austin, Doryan Winkleman, Ross Netherton, Nan Netherton, Joyce Pearsall, Levelle Dupel, Edith Sprouse, Virginia Peters, Mayo Stuntz, Suzanne Levy, Fairfax County Board of Supervisors, 1992 July 27 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Series 8: Financial Records, 1975-2005
  - Bank Statements, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Bicentennial Indexing Project: Books for Virginia Room Financial Statements, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Bicentennial Indexing/1860 Project, 1990-1996 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Budget FY 1989, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Budget FY 1990, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Budget FY 1991, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Budget FY 1992, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Budget FY 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Budget FY 1994, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Budget FY 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Budget FY 1996, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Budget FY 1997, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Budget FY 1998, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Budget FY 1999, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Budget FY 2000, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Budget FY 2001, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Budget FY 2002, 2001-2002 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Budget FY 2003, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Budget FY 2004, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Budget FY 2005, 2004-2005 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1975-1977 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Check Register, 1975-1977 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Gifts in Memory of Donald J. Senese, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - History Commission Budget, 1991-1997 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Marker Proffers, 2003-2005 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Markers, 1988-2005 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1975-1977 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Publication Sales, 2002-2005 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Publications - Battle of Chantilly, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Publications - City of Canvas, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Publications - Fairfax County Courthouse Monograph, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Publications - George Mason and the Legacy of Constitutional Liberty, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Publications - Preservation of History in Fairfax County, Va, 1992-2001 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Publications - Publicity, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Publications - Stewart House-Linden Lee, 1989-1992 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Publications - Union Mills/Stone Ground, 1991-2003 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Receipts, 1975-1977 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Series 9: Historical Marker Files, 1991-2018
  - Sub-series 9-1: Historical Markers, 1991-2018
    - A. Smith Bowman Distillery (never erected), 2003-2005 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Accotink Quarter (never erected), 2014 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Action at Annandale, 2009-2010 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Anne C. Williams Heights (never erected), 2005 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Bailey’s Crossroads [contains photos], 2000-2013 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Battle of Dranesville (cancelled), 2001-2006 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Beacon Field Airport, 2008-2010 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Benvenue [contains photos], 2000-2006 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Bethlehem Baptist Church, 2013-2014 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Birthplace of Fitzhugh Lee (VDHR marker) [contains photos], 2004 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Bog Wallow Ambush, 2011-2012 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Burgundy Farm Country Day School, Undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Camp Russell A. Alger (VDHR marker) [contains photos], 1993-2001 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Carroltown (revision), 2018 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Cartersville Baptist Church, 2003-2006 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Chantilly, 2010-2011 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Chesterbrook, 2015 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Civil War at Frying Pan Spring Meeting House, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Civilian Conservation Corps, 2007-2012 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Clover Hill, 2013-2014 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Colchester (VDHR marker) [contains photos], 1993-2000 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Colvin Run “Old Road West” VDHR-VDOT, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Colvin Run Mill (cancelled), 2001-2002 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Copperthite Racetrack, 2015 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Cross Farmhouse, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Cross Farm (revision), 2017 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - David R. Pinn Community Center, 2009-2010 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Deputy Sheriff George A. Malcolm, 2013-2014 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Fairfax Station, 2012 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - First Confederate Officer Killed (VDHR marker), 2008-2009 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Fort Lyon (VDHR marker), 1998-2002 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Franconia [contains photos], 2000-2012 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Goodings Tavern, 2011 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Guinea Road Cemetery Reinternment, 2005-2008 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Huldah Coffer House, 2012-2014 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Hunter Mill Road, 2009-2010 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Huntley (E-96) and Frying Pan Meeting House (T-43), 1994 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Hybla Valley Airport, 2010-2011 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Ilda, 2007-2010 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Ira Noel Gabrielson (VDHR marker), 2007-2008 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Ivakota Farm, 2006-2007 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - James Lee Elementary School, 2018 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Keene's Mill [contains photographs], 1995-2015 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Keyes House (never erected), 2004-2005 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Langley Fork, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Laughlin Building, 2011 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Laurel Grove Colored School and Church, 2008-2009 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Lincoln Reviews Troops at Bailey's Crossroads (T-40) and J.E.B. Stuart at Munson's Hill (T-39), 1992 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Lincolnsville, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Little River Turnpike, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Little Zion Baptist Church and Cemetery (never erected), 2010-2014 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Lorton Penitentiary, 2004-2016 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Lorton Reformatory, 2016 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Luther P. Jackson High School, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Manassas Gap Railroad Independent Line - Centreville Trail-Cub Run, 2003-2009 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Manassas Gap Railroad Independent Line - Shirley Gate, 2001-2013 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - McAtee’s Tavern, 2016 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - McLean, 2002-2003 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - McLean Volunteer Fire Department, Undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Mitchell-Weeks House, 2002-2003 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Mosby Attacks Annandale, 2009-2010 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Mount Air, 2006-2007 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Mount Pleasant Baptist Church, 2016 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Mount Pleasant Colored School (never erected), 2005 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Navy School (never erected), 2007 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Newington, 2003-2005 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Nike Missile Sites (VDHR markers), 1994-1995, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - NOVA Campus Heritage (never erected), 2010-2015 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Odrick’s Corner, 2001-2013 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Orange and Alexandria Railroad, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Orange and Alexandria Railroad Trestle, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Original Mount Vernon High School, 2014-2015 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - The Pines, 2015 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Price’s Ordinary [contains photos], 1999-2000 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Rose Hill, 2000-2013 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Saint Mark’s Episcopal Church, 2010-2011 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Salisbury Plain, 2004-2005 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Salona, 2003-2010 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Seven Corners Shopping Center / Fort Buffalo, 1992-1994 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Shiloh Baptist Church, 2010-2011 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Smith's Chapel (never erected), 2000 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Springfield Station, 1995-2015 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Sydenstricker Schoolhouse, 2016 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Army Map Service (VDHR marker), 2015-2016 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Vale School/Vale Community House, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Vienna Anti-Aircraft Gun Site, Undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Waple's Mill, 1999-2001 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - West Grove, 2011-2016 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Wharton Lane Civil War Bunker, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - William Watters, 2014-2015 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Sub-series 9-2: Historical Marker Subject Files, 1992-2015
    - Boundary Stones, 2000-2001 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Fairfax County Government Issues, 1999-2010 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - Historic Marker Committee, 1998-2003 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - VDHR, 1995-2015 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - VDOT, 2000-2005 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Henrico Historic Marker Program, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Historical Marker Program, 1992-1998 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Historical Markers - Miscellaneous, 1998-2003 (Box 23, Folder 8)